Guide to the District of Columbia Cable Television collection, 1972-1984 MS2376
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
District of Columbia Cable Television collection
1972-1984
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
D.C. Cable T.V. Design Commission
MS2376
3 Linear Feet
Collection consists of the records from the D.C. Cable TV Design Commission. In 1982 a commission was formally created by the Council of the District of Columbia to create a proposal for bringing cable television to the District of Columbia. This collection consists of documents from the D.C. Cable TV Design Commission including two of the bids for the project. The material dates from 1972-1984.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: District Telecommunications Development Corporation, Capital City Cable; DC Cable Design Commission Reports.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unknown.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports and project proposals. The material dates from 1972-1984. These are the records of the D.C. Cable TV Design Commission. The commission was established by the Council of the District of Columbia to bring cable TV to the entire District of Columbia.
Biographical / Historical
In 1982, the Council of the District of Columbia formally created the D.C. Cable TV Design Commission. This commission consisted of 28 members; their job was to create a proposal for bids for companies to install cable for the entirety of the District of Columbia. At the time that this commission was created, cable was only available to a few thousand apartments and homes in Southwest and Northwest DC. This project would make cable available to everyone.
The bidding came down to three companies: District Cablevision Inc., Capital City Cable and District Telecommunications Development Corporation. After some challenges with the scope and cost of the project, a final candidate was chosen and District Cablevision was given the contract. They were ideal because they were local, and were able to offer 79 channels which was 19 more channels than required.
United States -- District of Columbia -- Washington; Television; Cable television -- Washington (D.C.); Municiple franchises -- Washington (D.C.)
- District Telecommunications Development Corporation, 1983-1984; Series 1; 1 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged numerically by volume.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains proposals from the District Telecommunications Development Corporation for the DC Cable TV Design Commission. The material dates from 1983-1984.
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 1 [1/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 1 [2/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 1 [3/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 2 [1/2], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 2 [2/2], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 3 [1/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 3 [2/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 3 [3/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 4 [1/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 4 [2/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 4 [3/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 5 [1/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 5 [2/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 5 [3/3], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 6 [1/2], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 6 [2/2], 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - District Telecommunications Development Corporation Volume 7, 1983-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Capital City Cable, 1984; Series 2; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains proposals from Capital City Cable for the DC Cable TV Design Commission. The material is from 1984.
  - Capital City Cable Volume 1 [1/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 1 [2/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 1 [3/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 2 [1/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 2 [2/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 2 [3/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 3 [1/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 3 [2/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Capital City Cable Volume 3 [3/3], 1984; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- D.C. Cable Design Commission Reports, 1972-1983; Series 3; 1 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains reports and documents from the DC Cable TV Design Council. Material dates between 1972-1983.
  - Analysis of the Potential Role of the C&P Telephone Company..., 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Analysis of Single and Multiple Cable Franchise Options for the District of Columbia, 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - An Ascertainment of the Needs of Institutions and Organization D.C. [1/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - An Ascertainment of the Needs of Institutions and Organization D.C. [2/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cable Television Franchise Invitation for Applicants [1/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cable Television Franchise Invitation for Applicants [2/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cable Television for the Washington Metropolitan Area, 1972; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - D.C. Cable Television Design Commission Alternative Ownership Feasibility [1/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Cable Television Design Commission Alternative Ownership Feasibility [2/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Cable TV Taskforce Final Report [1/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - D.C. Cable TV Taskforce Final Report [2/2], 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fiber Optics Study, 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Programming Committee Final Report Volume 1, 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Programming Committee Final Report Volume 2, 1983; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 6)